(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-09T21:35:28.330656",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
鷹嶺ルイ生誕バンドライブ「L-challenger」にお越しのみなさん、
Everyone attending the Takane Lui Birthday Band Live,
まったかねー！
hello there!
ホロックスの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します。
I am Takane Lui, executive officer of Holox.
本日は街に待った生誕ライブ！
Today is the long-awaited birthday live!
開演に先立ちまして、注意事項をお知らせです。
Before the show starts, here are some important notices.
このライブは全編無料生バンドでお送りいたします。
This concert will be streamed free with a live band!
絶対に見逃せない超超超超超重大発表もございますので、最後までぜひ見てってくださいね！
There's also a super-duper mega-important announcement you can't miss, so please watch until the very end!
感想はハッシュタグ鷹嶺ルイ生誕バンドライブになっております。
Please use the hashtag #TakaneLuiBirthdayBandLive for your impressions.
SNSでスクショ付きでガンガンポストして盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if you post screenshots on SNS and hype it up.
そして本編終了後の21時15分からは、
And after the main show ends, starting at 9:15 PM,
メンバーシップ限定ライブもございます！
there will also be a membership-exclusive live!
メンバーシップライブももちろん生バンドで歌っちゃいますので、この機会にメンバーシップへのご参加お待ちしております！
The membership live will of course feature a live band performance, so I hope you'll join our membership!
さて、ここからがお知らせです！
Now, here are the announcements!
早く集まってくださった皆さんに、
For everyone who gathered early,
鷹嶺ルイ生誕記念2024グッズ情報を先出ししたいと思います！
I'd like to preview the Takane Lui Birthday Commemoration 2024 goods!
今回のグッズは4種類！最初は、こちら！
There are four types of goods this time! First up is this!
ライブといえばビッグタオル！
When it comes to lives, it's a big towel!
今回のライブテーマにぴったりの、かっこよく歌う私をかがげパパが描き下ろしてくれました！ありがとう！
Kagage-papa drew me singing coolly, fitting the live theme perfectly! Thank you!
大きなタオルなので、イベントで背中からかければ推し活をアピールできちゃいます！
It's a big towel, so you can show off your support by wearing it on your back at events!
続いてはこちら、ランダム缶バッジ！
Following that is this, random tin badges!
楽器を演奏する可愛いイラストが全4種類！1種類がランダムで封入されております。イラストはGurin.先生に描いていただきました！
Featuring cute illustrations of playing instruments across 4 types! One type is randomly included. The illustrations were drawn by Gurin.-sensei!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
これはね、すごくい可愛いので全種類集めたくなっちゃいますよね！
These are so cute that you'll definitely want to collect all of them!
続いてはこちら！おでかけルイぬいぐるみ！
Next is this! Going-out Lui plushie!
先日お披露目されたばかりの新衣装がぬいぐるみになって登場です！
The brand-new outfit just recently revealed is now available as a plushie!
かなりリクエストが多かった持ち運びしやすいサイズ…
With a size that had a lot of requests for easy portability...
になっておりますので、
It's become available,
いろんなところに連れていっていただければなと思います。
I hope you'll take it with you to various places!
最後はこちら、ボディ痛バ！
Lastly, we have the body痛 bag!
今回のランダム缶バッチやおでかけぬいぐるみとの相性もばっちりの痛バが登場です。
The random badges and out-and-about plushies go great with this!
私のモチーフがさりげなくあしらわれたデザインで、男女問わず使えるバッグになっております。
It features a subtle, stylish design suitable for anyone regardless of gender.
ストラップ位置を変えることでショルダーバッグにもなる2WAY仕様です。
By changing the strap position, it can also be used as a shoulder bag in 2 ways!
ぜひこれを持ってルイ推しを全力アピールしてください！
Please grab one of these and show your full support for Lui!
ということで、こちらの4種類のグッズがすべて入ったフルセットもご用意しております。
We've also prepared a full set containing all 4 types of goods!
フルセットには、箔押し複製サイン入りチケット風カードと特典ボイスがついております。
The full set includes a foil-stamped duplicate signature ticket-style card and a bonus voice!
今回はデジタル特典は数量限定バージョンでご用意させていただきました。
This time, the digital bonus features limited-edition content!
今回はですね、デジタルメッセージを心込めて入れさせていただきます。
This time, it includes a heartfelt digital message.
数量限定ですが、いつもより多めにご用意させていただきましたので、1人でも多くの方に手にとってもらえたら嬉しいです。
Although limited, we've prepared more than usual so many people can get one!
特典ボイスはライブの後の打ち上げパーティをイメージしたシチュエーションボイスになっております。
The bonus voice is a situational voice imagining an after-party following the live concert.
今回も私が台本を書かせていただきました。
I wrote the script this time as well!
こちらは通常も、限定バージョンにも共通で入ってくる特典になっておりますので、ぜひ聞いていただけると嬉しいです。
This will also be included in both regular and limited editions, so please be sure to listen!
グッズはこのライブ本編終了後の21時からホロライブプロダクションのオフィシャルショップで販売開始になります。
The goods will go on sale at the Hololive Production Official Shop starting at 21:00 after the live show!
ライブを楽しんだあとはグッズもよろしくね！
We hope you enjoy the merchandise after the live!
お待たせしました！鷹嶺ルイ生誕バンドライブ「L-challenger」まもなく開演です。
Takane Lui's Solo Band Live, "L-challe-nger," is coming soon!
この日のためにたくさん準備をしてきました！全力で歌うので最後までみんなで盛り上がっていきましょう！
We've prepared a ton for this day, so let's get hyped together until the very end!
準備はいいかー！
Are you ready?
それでは行きましょう！まずはオープニングアクトです。
Then let's go! First up is the opening act.
ボルテージを上げてくれるユニットといえば！
What unit can really pump up the voltage?
La LaPaTa Pa La LaPaTa
La LaPaTa Pa LaPuTa PaLa PaTaPaTa
no money 枯れた show 招待状
No money, faded show invitation.
「秘密で秘匿の異次元マンションへ！」
"Welcome to the secret, occult other-dimensional mansion!"
ガタガタのドアの笑い声に
With the giggling of the rickety door,
no pain, no gain アンチチェーン！
No pain, no gain, anti-chain!
狙う魔装のホークアイ
Targeting demonic magic hawk eyes,
迫る咆哮はウォークライ
approaching roars are a walk-cry.
放射状に突破口も ドウダロウ？の走馬灯
A breakthrough into radiation and what's-this reminiscence?
x に取り込まれてゆく…
Being absorbed into X...
刻印でござるー♪
It's an engraved memory— ♪
不条理な見学ツアー
An unreasonable field trip tour,
ドアからドアへイリューージョン
illusionary from door to door.
サーカス小屋よりピュアに響け 笑い声！
Resonating purely from the circus hut, the laughter!
La LaPaTa Pa La LaPaTa
La LaPaTa Pa La LaPaTa x!
La LaPaTa Pa LaPuTa PaLa PaTaPaTa
つまり本件
In short, the real deal.
力こそパワフルな
Raw power is truly powerful.
「迷宮のラビリンス」 (death)
"Labyrinthine Labyrinth" (death)!
並び立つシルエット
Silhouettes standing in a row,
恐怖！秒で切断 wi-fi
horror! Wi-Fi cut off in seconds.
これまじで最恐 room だけど
This is the scariest room so far, but
刃の回廊は 普通に危ないって
the corridor of blades is normally dangerous.
one shot, one kill
虚実 踊る マリオネット
Marionettes dancing in and out of reality.
墜ちる 部屋 は 何度目？と
How many times has the room fallen?
ランク外 は 眼中 ない が まぁくらい
Out-of-rank is out of mind, but
雷 あかんく ない ？
isn't lightning terrifying?
x に 取り込まれて kuku ku…
Absorbed into X, kuku ku...
迷える子羊くんたちー！
Lost little lambs!
おさとう、スパイス、そしてピンクなものいっぱいでハイになれるドリンクできたよー♪
Salt, spices, and everything pink—a high-inducing drink is ready~ ♪
ロックで飲んでくださいね ホロライブだけに (ははー)
Drink it on the rocks, just like Hololive (haha)!
さあ皆様殿 飲むでござるー
Now everyone, cheers!
吾輩 酔った
I'm already drunk...
いやお前が飲むんかい
No, you're the one drinking!
じゃとりあえず かんぱーい！！
Well anyway, cheers!!
鏡の回廊から
From the mirror corridor,
帝王の冷笑 警報
the Emperor's sneer warning.
塗り替えられる常夜に 爆ぜろ 笑い声！
Explode with laughter into the overwritten eternal night!
お前たちもな！
You guys too!
La LaPaTa Pa La LaPaTa
La LaPaTa Pa La LaPaTax!
La LaPaTa Pa La LaPaTa x!
La LaPaTa Pa La LaPaTa
La LaPaTa Pa LaPuTa PaLa PaTaPaTa
さあ集め！5人の元
Now gather! To the 5 of us,
迷いのない回路から
From a path without hesitation,
手本を見せ初めを
Show them the example from the start,
塗り替えられる常夜に
Into the repainted eternal night,
見出せよ
Discover it.
笑い声、お前たちも
Laughter, and you all as well,
集どえ ここの下
Gather here, under this place,
固く組んで 声を高らかに
Firmly link up and raise your voices high!
エデンの海を越えるため
To cross the sea of Eden,
つまり本気 複痛が痛い 敵な迷宮の
Meaning serious, a painful stomachache, of a wonderful labyrinth,
スーパーフューチャー パーティラビリンス
Super Future Party Labyrinth!
バイホロウ！
Bye Hollow!
鳥カゴにフリーキーショー
In the birdcage, a freaky show,
鍵開けで「私のセカイ」
Open the lock to "My World".
開幕初手無限リスタートです
Opening first move, infinite restart,
で？キミはカゴの雛
So? You are the chick in the cage.
ti ti ti li ta ti ti li ti ti la
ti ti ti li ta エデンはここに
ti ti ti li ta, Eden is right here.
爪を隠して(アイロニー) 誘ってあげる(愛をね)
Hiding claws (irony), inviting you (with love).
luiは友呼ぶ welcome to my little world！
Lui calls friends, welcome to my little world!
trip！！ 「Tori To Re:TreaT」
Trip!! "Tori To Re:TreaT"
ようこそ！鳥包みでね
Welcome! Wrapped in birds,
セカイを鳥こで満たして
Fill the world with birds.
「TreaT & Re:TreaT」 〈逃避行にご注意！〉
"TreaT & Re:TreaT"
カゴが揺れてるの？まあいいか
The cage is shaking? Oh well.
welcome！私のセカイへ くちばしの神バース
Welcome! To my world, the bird-beaked god birth.
さあシンフォニーを奏でて放て トリッキーに
Now, play and release the symphony, trickily.
道理 不条理の トリガーで 曖昧にチルいランチ はどう？
With the trigger of reason and absurdity, how about a vague, chill lunch?
揺れる カゴの ペンデュラム 鴫の目 鷹の目 が 回る
Swaying pendulum of the cage, snipe's eye, hawk's eye spinning.
ああもう、そう 戴冠 ね 招待状 で？ キミ は カゴ の 雛
Oh already, yes, coronation, invitation. So? You are the chick in the cage.
歪 の ヒミツ ( アイロニー ) 話して あげる ( 愛 を ね )
Secret of distortion (irony), telling you (with love).
飛ぶ 鷹 ( とり ) に 堕ちて welcome to my little world ！ trip ！ ！
Falling into the flying hawk, welcome to my little world! Trip!!
「 Tori To Re:TreaT 」 ようこそ ！ トリ 包み で ね セカイ が トリ こ で 満ちて いく
"Tori To Re:TreaT", Welcome! Wrapped in birds, the world filling with birds.
「 TreaT & Re:TreaT 」 〈 逃避行 に ご 注意 ！ 〉 振出 の welcome my world ！
"TreaT & Re:TreaT"  Reset to welcome my world!
「 Tori To Re:TreaT 」 ようこそ ！ トリ 包み で ね セカイ を トリ こ で 満たして
"Tori To Re:TreaT", Welcome! Wrapped in birds, fill the world with birds.
「 TreaT & Re:TreaT 」 ありえない ほど i ( 愛 ) を 揺らし て ね welcome ！ 私 の セカイ へ
"Tori To Re:TreaT", Shake love to an impossible degree, welcome! To my world.
ゆれる過去のペンデュラム
The swaying pendulum of the past,
うのめたかのめ回る
turning with greedy eyes.
あーもっとちょうだいなちょうだいよ
Ah, I want more, give me more!
みてて 君は過去の鳥籠
Watch closely, you're the birdcage of the past,
いびつの秘密
a distorted secret.
話してあげる
I'll tell you all about it.
とぶ鳥に落ちて Welcome to my little walkthrough!
Falling for the flying bird—Welcome to my little walkthrough!
とりどりどりど鳥籠の外に巻いてね
Scatter them all outside the birdcage,
世界は鳥籠で満ちてく
as the world fills up with birdcages.
とりどりどりど遠く側にごちそうを 繰り出す上の構えは
Feast spread far and wide outside the cage—ready to strike from above!
とりどりどりど鳥籠の外に巻いてね
Scatter them all outside the birdcage,
世界は鳥籠で満たして
filling the world with birdcages,
とりどりどりどありえない程の愛を
with an impossible amount of love!
揺らしてでっかい Welcome 私の世界へ
Rocking it big—Welcome to my world!
窓の外駆け出す サシとシモ重ねて話して
Running out the window, doubling up on greed and deceit as we talk.
今日、急速いなほりまで 世界をずっとひとり占めにするから この歌のラスト
Today, monopolize the world all the way to the fast-growing rice—this song's grand finale,
そうさ鳥が語るの
yes, that's what the bird tells you.
もういいじゃん ムキになっちゃって
Oh, come on, why are you getting so defensive?
カッコつけて カッコよくない
Trying to look cool, but failing miserably.
そういうの いやになってんだ
I'm so sick of that kind of attitude.
ほっといてよ 知りたくない
Just leave me alone, I don't want to know.
もういいじゃん やけになってんの？
Oh, come on, are you losing your mind?
嫉妬したり じっとできない
Being jealous and unable to stay still,
聞こえないよう耳塞いだって 言ってくんじゃん しんどいな
blocking your ears so you can't hear, yet still speaking up—how exhausting.
僕なんて誰も望んないよ
Nobody wants someone like me anyway,
だから僕のことそっとしといて
so just leave me quietly alone.
うっさい！だけど
Shut up! But
げにハイハイハイ受ける
seriously, hi-hi-hi, how hilarious.
まさの しまってるねだとか 本当は怯えてる吠える
Locking the door or whatever—truth is, you're just barking out of fear.
どうしたんだっだ
What's wrong with you?
痛いくせに耐えてハイハイハイ
Enduring even though it hurts—hi-hi-hi!
いつも平気なふりばっかなの
Always acting like everything's fine,
僕は壁を貼ったまま笑う それ以上近づかないで
I keep up my walls and smile—don't get any closer than that!
でっでっでっ怖いじゃん
Dee-dee-dee, it's scary, right?
ばかばっか ばかばっか ばかばっか やだ ばかばっか
Idiots, idiots, idiots, no way, total idiots!
もういいじゃん まだ怒ってんの
Oh, come on, are you still mad?
ほっといてよ ほっとできない
Just leave me alone—I can't just let it go.
見ないように目を逸らしたって 付いてくるじゃん やっぱり
Even if I look away so I don't see it, it keeps following me—figures.
転がったら起き上がればいいじゃん 失ったら探せばいいじゃん
If you fall, just get back up; if you lose something, just search for it!
いやいやいやいやいやいやや それじゃ良くない？
No way, no way, no way—isn't that not good enough?
間違ったら直せばいいじゃん やんなくなったらやめればいいじゃん
If you make a mistake, fix it; if you're done doing it, just stop!
いやいやいやいやいやいやや それじゃ良くない
No way, no way, no way—isn't that still no good?
僕は誰も望まないよ
Nobody wishes for someone like me,
だから僕のことそっとしといて
so just leave me quietly alone.
やなこと全部大丈夫だと言えたらいいのにな
I wish I could say that all the bad things are going to be okay.
思えたらいいのにな
I wish I could truly feel that way.
違うよってたらねえ大正解
"That's wrong," you say? Bullseye, absolutely right!
いつも僕は損なロールなの また言いたいことを殺す
I'm always playing the losing role, killing the things I want to say yet again.
だからもう忘れてくれ わっはっはっ
So just forget about it already—wah-ha-ha!
うっさい！だけどバカにハイハイハイ
Shut up! But hi-hi-hi to the idiots,
受ける！またの越し待ってるねだとか
how hilarious! Waiting for your next visit or whatever—
本当は怯えてる吠えるだけの弱虫
truth is, you're just a coward barking out of fear.
痛いくせに耐えてハイハイハイ
Enduring even though it hurts—hi-hi-hi!
いつも平気なふりばっかなの
Always acting like everything's fine,
僕は壁を貼ったまま笑う それ以上近づかないでって でっでっでっ暗いじゃん
I keep up my walls and smile—don't get any closer than that! Dee-dee-dee, it's so gloomy, right?
ほんとばかばっか いい加減ばかばっか 飛んだバグばっか 出せなくて
Seriously, total idiots, enough with the idiots, flying bugs everywhere, unable to put it out—
そんなことばっか思う僕もやっぱどうしようもないんだって
even someone like me who thinks about stuff like that is totally hopeless.
定期型耐えらんないないない 死ねるって僕も口ばっかでね
Can't take the routine anymore, saying I could just die, but it's all talk.
今日も壁を貼ったまま笑う それ以上近づかないでって でっでっでっ暗いじゃん
Today too, I keep my walls up and smile—don't get any closer than that! Dee-dee-dee, it's so gloomy, right?
ばかばっか ほらばかばっか
Idiots, look, total idiots!
ということが改めまして ちょっと喉がヤバい
And with that, once again—my throat is in serious trouble!
膝もやばい 大丈夫？
And my knees are shot too! Are you okay?
大丈夫でしょ？ っていうかちょっと水飲んできてもいいですか？
Are you okay? Wait, can I go drink some water?
そうですね 飲みたいとも
Yeah, absolutely, you should drink some.
あっじゃあカニ 自己紹介をして貰っててもらっても？
Then, Mori, would you mind introducing yourself?
オッケーです まかせて
Got it, leave it to me!
みなさーん いつも頑張ってる死神 カリオペ・モリです よね ホロライブEnglishの死神デスデス！ 破滅はここデスデス！
Everyone! It's your hardworking grim reaper, Mori Calliope! Right, Hololive English's reaper is death-death! Ruin is right here, death-death!
Hey everyone! Thank you for watching!
いやー楽しい おごめごめごめ
Man, this is so fun—sorry, sorry, sorry!
楽しすぎる
It's just too fun!
いやー今日は来てくれてありがとうございます
Man, thank you so much for coming today.
いやいや こちらこそおさざってくれてありがとうございます
No, no, thank you so much for supporting us!
歌いたかったんで
I really wanted to sing it,
そうだね、すごい好きな曲。
That's right, such a favorite song.
なんかめちゃめちゃ緊張してた、実は。
Actually, I was super, super nervous.
でもめちゃめちゃかっこよかったです。
But it was super cool.
そうだね。そして、なんか
That's right. And also, like,
バンドもいるよね。そう。
there's a live band too. Yeah.
すごい！わあ、本当にびっくりした！
Amazing! Wow, I was really surprised!
生バンドでお送りしております。
bringing it to you with a live band.
かっこいい！
Cool!
めちゃめちゃかっこいい！
Super, super cool!
これからもちょっと生バンドでお送りしたいと思いますので。
We'd like to continue delivering it with a live band,
ああ、ハッシュタグ鷹嶺ルイ生誕バンドライブで、たくさんつぶやいてくださると嬉しいです。使って使って。
So we'd be happy if you could tweet a lot with the hashtag Takane Lui Birthday Band Live. Please use it, use it.
はい、今トレンド4位みたいなのなので。うわ！お！
Yeah, it's currently around #4 on trending. Wow! Oh!
1位まで押し上げてくれ！お願いします！頑張ってみんな、お願い！
Push it up to #1! Please! Do your best everyone, please!
ということでね、蟹が出てきたということは、ここから実はゲストパートになるので、収録もしてあるんですけど、バンドの、これもねバンドなので、ぜひゲストパートをこれから3曲続けて見ていただければなと思います。その間に喉を休めてきます。
So, the fact that Kani appeared means that from here on it's actually the guest part, so we've recorded it, but since this is also a band, we'd love for you to watch the guest part for 3 songs straight from now on. In the meantime, I'll go rest my throat.
ということでね、蟹、ありがとう！
So, Kani, thank you!
いやいや、こちらこそ楽しかった！
No, no, I had a blast!
じゃ、一緒にパートちょっと振ってもらってもいいですか？
Then, can I have you help wave parts together with me?
オッケーです。
Okay.
ということでね、ゲストパートに、スターター！スタート！レッツゴー！
So, for the guest part, starter! Start! Let's go!
籠の中でフリーキーショー
A freaky show in a cage
鍵開けて?「私のセカイ」
Open the lock? "My world"
開幕初手無限リスタートでしょ?キミは籠の巣窟
An infinite restart right at the start? You are the cage's nest
ti ti ti li ta ti ti li ti ti la
ti ti ti li ta エデンはここに
ti ti ti li ta Eden is right here
爪を隠して(アイロニー)
Hiding claws (Irony)
誘ってあげる(愛をね)
Inviting you (Love)
Luiは友呼ぶ welcome to my little world! trip!!
Lui calls friends, welcome to my little world! trip!!
「Tori To Re:TreaT」
"Tori To Re:TreaT"
ようこそ!トリ囲んでね
Welcome! Surround the birds
世界をトリこで満たして
Fill the world with captives
「TreaT&Re:TreaT」
"TreaT&Re:TreaT"
〈逃避行にご注意!〉
〈Beware of escape!〉
籠が揺れているの?まあいいか
The cage is swaying? Oh well
welcome!私のセカイへ
Welcome! To my world
くちばしの神バース
Beak's divine verse
さあシンフォニーを奏でて放てトリッキーに
Now play the symphony and release it trickerly
道理不道理のトリガーで
With the trigger of unreasonable reason
曖昧にチルいランチはどう?どう?どう?
How is a vague chill lunch? How? How? How?
揺れる籠のペンデュラム
The swaying cage pendulum
鴫の目鷹の目が回る
Snipe's eye, hawk's eye spins
ああもう、そう御戴ね招待状
Oh my, indeed accepted, the invitation
で?キミは籠の巣窟
So? You are the cage's nest
歪のヒミツ(アイロニー)
Secret of distortion (Irony)
話してあげる(愛をね)
Talking to you (Love)
飛ぶ鷹に堕ちて welcome to my little world! trip!!
Falling to the flying hawk, welcome to my little world! trip!!
「Tori To Re:TreaT」
"Tori To Re:TreaT"
ようこそ!トリ囲んでね
Welcome! Surround the birds
セカイがトリこで満ちていく
The world is filling with captives
「TreaT&Re:TreaT」
"TreaT&Re:TreaT"
〈逃避行にご注意!〉
〈Beware of escape!〉
振り出しのwelcome my world!
Welcome my world from scratch!
「Tori To Re:TreaT」
"Tori To Re:TreaT"
ようこそ!トリ囲んでね
Welcome! Surround the birds
世界をトリこで満たして
Fill the world with captives
「TreaT&Re:TreaT」
"TreaT&Re:TreaT"
ありえないほどi(愛)を
An unbelievable amount of love
揺らしてね welcome!私のセカイへ
Shake it, welcome! To my world
的はずれガイダンス
Misdirected guidance
さあ嫉妬心も重ねて離せ トリッキーに
Now overlapping jealousy too, release it trickerly
狂気嘘吐きなポリーマーで
With a mad, lying polymer
セカイをずっと巣窟にするから!
Making the world a nest forever!
この歌のラスト
The last of this song
こんなトリ飾るのはどう?
How about decorating like this?
ほらほらほくほくだけど
Look, look, steaming hot, but
本骨身がちょいあるだけで新鮮カンソウ
Just a little core of bone, fresh impression
そのサイソウそのサイソウさ受け止めてよね
Accept that re-creation, that re-creation
高嶺の未来乾杯
Toast to Takane's future
しっかりウォッチ 相槌うな 借りとか苦手
Watch closely, nod along, bad at borrowing,
巻く縫いね 逆からね
Wind and sew from reverse,
意外とギャップ系 イメージ大変身 オッケー！
Surprisingly gap moe, major image transformation, okay!
単色のコンセプト 内装じゃない
Monochrome concept, not interior design,
心配ねそうだね 残念でも
Worrisome, yeah, even if unfortunate,
妥協生のいや 孤独の配信じゃない
No to compromised life, not a lonely stream,
個人って聞いてる世界 ほらほらほくほくだけど
A world I hear is personal, look, look, steaming hot, but
飽食しのいさ だから怖がっちゃいや
Satiated appetite, so don't be scared,
ほらネツメも ハネも おしゃれにといで隠しちょい内
Look, heating up, feathers too, sharpen stylishly, hiding a bit inside
ほらほらほくほくほくほくだけど
Look, look, steaming hot, steaming hot, but
関節めがちょいあるだけで
Just a little joint-like part
緊張点その サイソウそのサイソウさ受け止めてよね
Tension point, that re-creation, that re-creation, accept it
高嶺の未来乾杯
Toast to Takane's future
ほらほらほくほくほくほくだけど
Look, look, steaming hot, steaming hot, but
ポンコツ身がちょいあるだけで 新鮮カンソウ
Just a bit of clumsy self, fresh impression
そのサイソウそのサイソウさ受け止めてよね
That re-creation, that re-creation, accept it
高嶺の未来乾杯
Toast to Takane's future
愛ちゃん高まる時代乾杯
Aichan, toast to the surging era
大体どうにでもなる事に どうにもならない様子なのは
When things that could easily go either way seem totally helpless,
どうにもこうにも動かず ただ 悲劇達が嘆いているから
and without moving an inch, tragedies simply lament,
悲しみだけが充満しているように見える世界ならば
in a world that looks completely filled with sorrow,
今は嘘でも強がりでも笑っていたいと思ってるんだよ
I want to keep smiling right now, even through pretense.
馬鹿げた毎日でいいなんて君は言うから
Since you say ridiculous days are fine,
ふざけた人類だって愛おしいって許せたんだよ
I could forgive even this foolish humanity as endearing.
僕がミスばっかりかばったって君は笑うから
Whenever I cover up all my mistakes, you just laugh,
僕はいつでもどんな時も助かってるんだよ
and that saves me at any time and in any situation.
世界で一番ふざけたヤヤヤ
The most ridiculous in the world, yeah!
果たすその日まで
Until the day we fulfill it,
あなたのまわりもヨヨヨ
all around you too, yo!
約束の地まで
until the promised land.
今日も期待 そんちのごたねぇ家にになるから
Today too, expecting... since it'll feel like home,
私一人でも やってやぎもすねぇ
even if I'm all alone, I'll pull it off.
すべてすべてすべてまき散らしてそれをさせてよ
Scatter everything, everywhere, and let me do it—
大事なことなの 分かっているでしょ
you know that's the most important thing.
白く空中浮遊 帰りの階段 面倒くさ、今も明日も続いていくのでしょう
Floating white in the air on the stairs home, troublesome, it'll keep going today and tomorrow too.
壁に目処をあゆまそう 時の中 忘れたこと忘れてた
Let's aim at the wall, forgetting what we forgot in the flow of time.
馬鹿げた毎日でいいなんて君は言うから
Since you say ridiculous days are fine,
ふざけた人類だって愛おしいって許せたんだよ
I could forgive even this foolish humanity as endearing.
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね
I want you to be just a little quiet,
私たち待望え
our long-awaited...
今は未来見たかったはずなのに
Even though I should have wanted to see the future now,
世界で一番ふざけたヤヤヤ
the most ridiculous in the world, yeah!
見えるその日まで
Until the day it comes into view,
込もむこだわりヨヨヨ
deep insistence, yo, yo, yo,
約束の地まで
until the promised land.
世界で一番ふざけたヤヤヤ 果たすその日まで
The most ridiculous in the world, yeah, until the day we fulfill it,
あなたのまわりもヨヨヨ 約束の地まで
all around you too, yo, until the promised land,
散々髪をばってんしてたら
if I keep messing up my hair,
明日の夜明けを明けましょう
let's bring on tomorrow's dawn.
誰かに言われなくたって 私のほうがもっと嫌いだ
Even if no one tells me, I hate myself even more.
私の方がもっと嫌いだ うるさいな 想像が視界を塞いで
How annoying, imagination blocks my vision,
教室にずっと居残り 窓の向こうに黒い影があって
Staying late in the classroom, with a black shadow beyond the window,
何も言わずにこっちを見ていた 私は貴方に救われたくて泣くんじゃない
looking at me without a word. I'm not crying because I want to be saved.
産声を止められないもの 何千回ともう一度死に損なおう
A birth cry cannot be stopped; let's fail to die once more.
希望と絶望の夜中を纏いで 醜い光を許したいのは 他ならぬ私だった
Wrapping the midnight of hope and despair, the one who wanted to accept this light was myself.
息をして目を開けて これが最後かどうか 知る術はないよ 知りたくもないよ
Breathe and open your eyes, whether this is the last time—there's no way of knowing.
優しくないな 昏々 間は寄り添って 解けない答えを塗り潰した
How unkind, the intervals snuggle close, painting over insoluble answers.
どうせ面白くもないよと 窓を挟んで微かに聞こえた
Faintly heard across the window, saying it's not even interesting anyway—
それは祈るような啜り泣きだった 私は貴方を救える言葉を知らないけど
that was a sobbing cry like a prayer. I don't know the words to save you, but
寂しいねって声をかけた 何千回ともう一度死に損なおう
I called out, "It gets lonely." Let's fail to die once more, thousands of times.
希望と絶望の夜中を纏いで 何千回ともう一度生きる貴方へ私も続くよ
Wrapping the midnight of hope and despair, I will follow you to where you live.
窓の向こう側で 醜い光を愛せたとき 終わらせなかった産声を 謳にしよう
Beyond the window, when we could love that ugly light, let's turn the birth cry into a song!
これが最後かどうか 知る術はないよ 知りたくもないよ
Whether this is the last time or not—there's no way of knowing, I don't want to know.
優しくないな
How unkind.
闇に溶けて 溶けて 溶けて 溶けていく
Dissolving into the darkness, dissolving away...
ネオンライトの透き間走って
Running through the gaps of neon lights,
潜って くぐっていく
Diving, passing right through.
透明な 深い夜に笑い合った
We laughed together in the clear, deep night,
生ぬるい風がなでていた
Caressed by a lukewarm breeze.
淡い記憶 全部覚えている
I remember every faint memory.
共鳴した 君の声音が宇宙の隅で
Your resonant voice in the corner of the cosmos
飛び散った後に光っていた
Shone brightly after scattering away.
遥か遠く 夢を見ていたんだ
I was dreaming of a distant place.
いつまでもずっと このままで居よう
Let's stay just like this forever and ever.
夢が覚めてしまう言葉
Words that would wake me from this dream,
今はまだ聞きたくないから 耳を塞いでいた
I don't want to hear just yet, so I covered my ears.
胸が裂けて 裂けて 裂けて 裂けていく
My heart is tearing apart, tearing apart...
ネオンライトの透き間走って
Running through the gaps of neon lights,
潜って くぐっていく
Diving, passing right through.
風を切って 切って 切って 切って行く
Cutting through the wind, cutting through...
グッバイ もうすぐ夜が 終わって 沈んでいく
Goodbye, the night will soon end and sink away.
幻想みたいに滲んだ光を ずっと眺めていた
I kept gazing at the light blurred like an illusion.
星影が 残る夜にぶつけ合った
Colliding in the night where starlight lingers,
ひりついた本音吐いた
Spilling out raw, stinging honest feelings.
苦い痛み 全部零れていく
All the bitter pain spills away.
立派なこの羽根に 泥つけて這っていた
Crawling through the mud with these fine wings,
兼ね備えた爪立てて 信じられる者は自分だけだと
Digging in my claws, believing only in myself,
思い込んで進み続けた
I kept moving forward, convinced of that.
「あの子みたいにすれば？」
“Why don’t you do it like that girl?”
「君じゃそれは無理だ」
“It’s impossible for you.”
言わせておけばいいさ
Let them say what they want.
たった独り逆境の先 あいつらから奪う歓声
Alone, beyond adversity, I will steal their cheers.
私の邪魔させやしない
I won’t let them hinder me.
like a 高峰 見据えた高み
Like a lofty peak, I gaze at the heights.
穴ぐらから空へ 飛んでいく私を見ないなんて bad boy
How could you not notice me flying away from a cave to the sky? Bad boy.
失敗は止まった時 今日も挑み這っている
Failure is when you stop; today again, I crawl and challenge.
意味のないものはないと 信じられるものを見つけ出すまで
Until I find something I can believe in, knowing nothing is meaningless,
どんな日だって笑い飛ばすんだ
I will laugh off every single day.
「あの子はもう終わりだ」
“That girl is done.”
「これ以上はないね」
“She won’t get any further.”
言わせておけばいいさ
Let them say what they want.
ダダラッタ ダダラッタ...
Da-da-rat-ta...
あの子はもう終わりだ これ以上はないね
That girl is done, she won't get any further.
いつの日か 寝ても覚めても 夢見てた大歓声
Whether asleep or awake, I've dreamed of the great cheers.
私はここで死にしたくない！
I don't want to die here!
一緒に旅 逆境の先 あいつらから奪う歓声
A shared journey, beyond adversity, I will steal their cheers.
私の邪魔させやしない like a 高峰 見据えた高み
I won't let them hinder me, like a lofty peak, I gaze at the heights.
穴ぐらから空へ 飛んでいく私を見ないなんて bad boy
How could you not notice me flying away? Bad boy.
バッドボーイ
Bad boy...
はい、ということで、3曲ゲストパートをお届けして、え、先ほど「カリスマ」という、え、jon-YAKITORYさんから、え、書き下ろしていただいた
Yes, with that, we delivered a guest part with 3 songs, and earlier we had "Charisma", written and composed for us by jon-YAKITORY,
楽曲を歌わせていただきました。いかがだったでしょうか。
we got to perform that song. How was it?
いぇーい！
Yay!
とゆーことで、ちょっとね、喉も回復したので、
So, um... my throat has recovered,
えー、歌えてよかったなと、思いますけれども、いやー
so I'm glad I could sing, but man...
あ、トレンドが1位になったそうで、みんなありがとう、たくさんつぶやいてくれて、あ、ポストしてくれてたね。
Oh, it seems our trend hit #1! Everyone, thank you so much for tweeting—ah, posting about it.
ポストしてくれてありがとう。まだまだたくさんの、え、ポストしてくれると嬉しいです。
Thank you for posting! I'd be so happy if you keep posting.
ハッシュタグ鷹嶺ルイ生誕バンドライブです、みんなありがとう！
The hashtag is Takane Lui Birthday Band Live! Thank you everyone!
いや、今回はね、あのもうすでに、えーリリースされている楽曲に関しては、えー
And for this time, um, for the songs that have already been released, um...
カリ先輩と、そしてマリーン先輩、おかゆ先輩、そしてトワ様とね、一緒に歌わせていただいたんですけど、
I got to sing together with Calli-senpai, Marine-senpai, Okayu-senpai, and Towa-sama,
まったくね、まったく違った感じになってて、私も楽しかったなと思うんですけど、みなさんいかがだったでしょうか？
and it turned out with a totally different vibe, which I thought was super fun. How was it for everyone?
いかがだったかな？おめでとう、おめでとう、ありがとう、ありがとう、みんなありがとう、楽しかったかな？
How was it? Congrats, congrats, thanks, thanks, thanks everyone, did you have fun?
あ、ホロホークがめちゃくちゃよかった。ホロホークって言ってる海外にいるね。ありがとう！
Ah, "HoloHawk was amazing." People overseas are saying HoloHawk. Thank you!
はい、なんかあのコメントがすごい勢いで流れているので、固まってしまいました。ありがとう！
Yes, um, the comments are flowing so fast, I completely froze up. Thank you!
とゆーことで、これからね、あの、2曲歌わせていただくんですけども、えー2曲で、あのーちょっとあの本編は終了
So, um, from here, I'll be singing two songs, and um, after those two songs, um, the main part will end—
うそです！あの、2曲以降もあるんですけども、一応2曲ね、これから続けて歌わせていただきます。
Just kidding! Um, there are more after two songs, but for now, we'll continue singing two songs from here.
次に歌う曲なんですけども、えー、FAKE TYPE.さんに、え、書き下ろししていただいた楽曲をやらせていただきます。「秘密のお仕事」という楽曲なんですけれども、めちゃくちゃかっこいい楽曲になっているので、えーぜひちょっと楽しんで聞いていただければなと思います。
The next song I'm going to sing is a track written for me by FAKE TYPE., called "Secret Job". It's such a cool song, so I hope you all enjoy listening to it!
その前にちょっと、水を飲んでもいいですか？いいよ、ということで水を飲みまーす。
Before that, do you mind if I drink some water? Sure, so I'll drink some water.
よし、歌える。俺ならいける。いけるよね？
Alright, I can sing. I can do this. Right?
みんな、いけるよね？とゆーことで、えー
Everyone can do this, right? So, um...
これから歌わせていただく曲は、FAKE TYPE.さんに書き下ろししていただいた楽曲、もうボロボロだ！楽曲「秘密のお仕事」です。ぜひ聞いてください。
The song I'm performing next is the track written for me by FAKE TYPE.—man, I'm falling apart!—the song "Secret Job". Please listen to it!
くそ野郎の “K”
A bastard's "K"
Do or nothing ボロ儲け
Do or nothing, making a killing
瞬く間に Invite 絶望百景の刑(Kick it)
In the blink of an eye, invited to a hundred views of despair (Kick it)
何にもやりたくない どうにもこうにもやりたくない
I don't wanna do anything, no matter what I just don't wanna do it
お仕事やりたくない やだやだ死んでもやりたくない
I don't wanna work, no way, I'd rather die than work
ガミガミ女神の怒号が飛び交う
The goddess's nagging roars fly around
働け働け You have to work hard
Work, work, you have to work hard
四六時中パシャリ ほぼ強制 All day all night long 馬車馬のように
Snapping pictures around the clock, practically forced, all day all night long like a workhorse
パジャマ寝坊助でいたいだけ 貴女の言うがまま
I just want to be a sleepyhead in pajamas, just as you say
超ワガママ暴君だから どうどう諭そうとしても
You're a super selfish tyrant, no matter how I try to reason with you
I’m an invisible busy boy
I'm an invisible busy boy
五月雨にいきなりの願望 下手打ちあお決まりの蛮行
Sudden desires in the early summer rain, botched moves, classic brutality
果てしない展望 向こう見ずな言動
Endless prospects, reckless words and deeds
空回り必須で理解追いつかない Hysteric
Bound to spin my wheels, comprehension can't keep up, Hysteric
意気揚々 魑魅魍魎 知らぬ間に横行
In high spirits, demons and monsters running rampant unnoticed
利かんなあまあもう手遅れなのよ
Can't you tell? Well, it's already too late
時期尚早 死に装束 へらってても Here we go now
Premature, death shroud, even if weary, here we go now
創らないかあの世へ Falling down
Shall we build it? To the other world, Falling down
Kruel Kreator...
Betray, Talking shit, Kill them all by M.I.C
Oh my “F” word, Please repair my broken heart (あらら)
Oh my "F" word, Please repair my broken heart (Oh my)
I still can’t forget the drama (怨嗟・贅土)
I still can't forget the drama
I must be an avenger , so tame the trauma (一切皆苦)
I must be an avenger, so tame the trauma
I can’t trust you ever , goodbye I ’m out
I can't trust you ever, goodbye I'm out
Stupid mo fxxker, shut up mo fxxker
I wanna get out of hell
Life is strange... I can't wait for the day I can beat you
Life is strange... Viva la revolución
やらねばやられる 逸っては暴れる 気持ち抑えて 震えて焦がれていたいい
Kill or be killed, rushing and rampaging, suppressing my feelings, shivering and yearning
かまさないと奪われる 運命に抗う 邪悪さは地獄絵図 silent night
If I don't hit back, it'll be stolen, fighting destiny, wickedness is a hellish tableau silent night
Just like a ninja 超高速で 背後から
Just like a ninja at hyper-speed from behind
肉切り包丁のクリティカルヒットで 攻防もなく 終わる か と 思 い き や oh no no !
With a critical hit from a meat cleaver, ending without even a defense—or so I thought, oh no no!
眠床に 腕 押し さ な が ら 殆 ど ち っ と も 当 た ら な い
Pushing my arm against the pillow, hardly hitting at all
気付いた時には背水の陣 刹那 相見え得る
By the time I notice, it's a last stand, momentarily crossing paths
Who the fxxk ?
Who the fxxk?
あれ ? 君 どこ で 会 っ た こ と あ る よ う な な い よ う な 雰 囲 気
Huh? You have a vibe like we've met somewhere before
てか それ ハイ クォリティ な アーテ ィスト て こ と は あの 時 に キ ズ ! ?
Wait, you're a high-quality artist—does that mean back then...?
Unbelievable 知らず知らずに I made a deal with the devil
Unbelievable, unknowingly I made a deal with the devil
Kruel Kreator... 狂う クリエーター
Kruel Kreator... a mad creator
このままじゃ 酔生夢死 の 末路 そんな ん 耐 え ら れ な い
At this rate, a wasted life's end—I can't endure that
だから 脳 に 刻 む 今 に 見 て ろ 白く 燃 ゆ る my ambition
So I carve it into my brain, just wait and see, my white-burning ambition
鳥カゴにフリーキーショー
A freak show inside a birdcage,
鍵開けて?「私のセカイ」
unlock it? "My world."
幕開け初手無限リスタートです
Opening move, an infinite restart,
で?キミはカゴの囮
so? You're the decoy in the cage.
Ti ti ti li ta Ti ti li Ti ti la
Ti ti ti li ta エデンはここに
Ti ti ti li ta, Eden is right here!
爪を隠して(アイロニー)
Hiding your claws (irony),
誘ってあげる(愛をね)
I'll invite you (with love, ya know).
Luiは友呼ぶ
Lui calls her friends,
Welcome to my little world!
Trip!!
「Tori To Re:TreaT」
"Tori To Re:TreaT"
ようこそ!トリ囲んでね
Welcome! Surrounded by birds,
ラストはこの曲です
The last song is this one.
皆さん聞いてください 魔眼ウインク
Everyone, please listen: "Magan Wink".
シャッターの目が 捉えきれなかった
The shutter's eye couldn't fully capture
ナイーズメロも真紅から それはウィングウィング
even the naive melody, from crimson—that's wing, wing!
逃げてもずっと真紅から I crave still, like typhoon's eye.
Even if you run, from crimson—I crave still, like typhoon's eye.
Wink! 正面おめめがでかい
Wink! Big front eyes,
目に入れといた 痛くないくらい
small enough to put in your eye without hurting.
ラララ 口紅にして
La la la... Make it lipstick,
Sweets Avenger 育くみなら
Sweets Avenger, if you're raising it,
特別にした 怖がってんの?ん、あっそう
make it special. Are you scared? Hm, is that so?
ゾッとしてみよう?
Let's give you a thrill, shall we?
まだまだ 飛び跳ねて
Jump around even more,
安全じゃないから 健全じゃないから
because it's not safe, because it's not wholesome,
それがなんだパーティだね
that's what a party is!
目には目を 牙には牙を
An eye for an eye, a fang for a fang,
平穏なんてクソ食らえ
to hell with peace!
Coming back, coming back, coming back!
盲目じゃない 常識じゃないだろ
Not blind, not common sense, right?
才能じゃないだろ それがどうしたパーティだね
Not talent, right? So what if it is, it's a party!
目には目を 牙には牙を
An eye for an eye, a fang for a fang,
Wink! セララララビー Singular なキミへ
Wink! Seraralalaby, to the singular you,
Wink! セララララヤマッカッカだ
Wink! Seraralalaya, totally red-hot!
Oh I, I, I want you de-bye-bye yonda
Oh I, I, I want you de-bye-bye-yonda
目にもの見せるまい I, I, I, いいよ
I'll show you what's coming, I, I, I, alright,
目を瞑る半分ね 魔眼ウインク
close your eyes halfway, "Magan Wink".
ほらごらん また巧みに
Look there, once again skillfully
I, I, I kill you, wink!
後ろ指さしたいなら お好きにどうぞ
If you want to point fingers behind my back, go right ahead.
どうせ 振り返らんの所存残り際
After all, looking back is just lingering attachment,
お待たせゾックゾック おさらばオオカミココ
keeping you thrilled to pieces, goodbye, wolf here!
ヘイコーなドクターリメ
Biased doctor remedy,
Coming back, coming back, coming back!
盲目じゃない 学習じゃないだろ
Not blind, not learned, right?
常識じゃないだろ 才能じゃないだろ
Not common sense, right? Not talent, right?
それがどうしたパーティだね 目には目を 牙には牙を
So what if it is, it's a party! An eye for an eye, a fang for a fang,
羽には羽を
a wing for a wing!
Wink! セララララビー Singular なキミへ Give me a wink!
Wink! Seraralalaby, to the singular you, give me a wink!
セララララヤマッカッカだ
Seraralalaya, totally red-hot!
Oh I, I, I want you de-bye-bye-yonda
目にもの見せるまい I, I, I, いいよ
I'll show you what's coming, I, I, I, alright,
目を瞑る半分ね 魔眼ウインク
close your eyes halfway, "Magan Wink".
完璧なウインク
A flawless wink!
セララララビー Singular なキミへ Give me a wink!
Seraralalaby, to the singular you, give me a wink!
セララララヤマッカッカだ
Seraralalaya, totally red-hot!
Oh I, I, I want you de-bye-bye-yonda
目にもの見せるまい I, I, I, もう目が話せない
I'll show you what's coming, I, I, I, I can't take my eyes off you anymore!
I, I, 魔眼ウインク
I, I, "Magan Wink".
ほらごらん また巧みに
Look there, once again skillfully
I, I, I kill you, wink!
ウインク
Wink...
はい、ということで
Yes, so,
重大告知させていただきました！
I've just made a major announcement!
重大告知は、なんと……！
And that major announcement is...
鷹嶺ルイ ファーストアルバム『Liberty』が
Takane Lui's 1st album, "Liberty,"
リリース決定です！
has been announced for release!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あ、みんなね、拍手してくれてますね。ありがとうございます。
Ah, everyone's clapping, thank you!
こちらの、えー、鷹嶺ルイのファーストアルバム『Liberty』皆さん、予想できていましたでしょうか？
Were you able to guess Takane Lui's 1st album, "Liberty"?
今回はですね、あのホロックスの1曲はあったんですけれネ、
This time, aside from one song featured on Hololive,
全曲、そのほかの曲は全曲鷹嶺ルイのオリジナル曲で、えー、ライブをさせていただきました。
all other songs are original tracks by Takane Lui!
えー、この楽曲が全部入った『Liberty』、
The album containing all these tracks, "Liberty,"
21時(じ)からホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで販売開始になります！
will go on sale at the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP starting at 21:00!
デジタルリリースはこの後24時から、
Digital releases will begin after this at 24:00
各種音楽サイトで配信が開始されます。
on various music streaming sites!
えー、『魔眼ウインク』とね、今日お披露目した新曲を含む、
Featuring "Magank Wink" and today's new song,
全10曲のオリジナルアルバムになっております。
it's an original album consisting of a total of 10 tracks!
収録、あ、しゅしゅしゅ、収録……収録内容は、こちら！はい、こちらですね。
Here is the tracklist:
秘密のお仕事、先ほど、えー、やらさせていただいた秘密のお仕事、魔眼ウインクに始まり、先輩とやったバーカバーカ、ファーストクライ、カリスマ、オーバード、トリートリートリート、ホロホーク、
Starting with "Himitsu no Oshigoto" and "Magank Wink," "Baka Pakka," "First Cry," "Charisma," "Overdose," "Tori To Re:Treat," "Horo Hawk,"
そして、「あれ？なんか夢ができたの、翼」まだやってないなっていう曲もありますけれども、
and a yet-unreleased song, "Yume ga Dekita no, Tsubasa."
この10曲が入った、えー、アルバムになっております。
This 10-track album is set for release!
アルバムジャケットのイラストはSOLANI先生に描いていただきまして、
The album jacket illustration was drawn by SOLANI-sensei,
ロゴは、えー、saku39先生に作っていただきました。
and the logo was designed by saku39-sensei!
えー、オフィシャルショップでのね、購入特典として、ミュージックビデオから厳選したシーンのカットの、えー、げん、厳選したシーンのカットフィルム風、えー、しおりをランダム封入させていただきます。
As a purchase bonus from the official shop, we're including a random film-style bookmark selected from music video scenes!
全4種類って書いてあるんですが、シークレットもあるので全5種類のなかから1枚封入ですね。
There are 4 regular types plus 1 secret type, for a total of 5 types.
さらに、直筆サイン入りのアナザージャケットもついてきちゃいます！こちら。
Plus, we've also included another jacket featuring a direct signature!
いや、かっこいいですね、白黒で。はい、こちら、購入者全員に直筆サインで書いていただきますので、
Every purchaser will get a direct signature,
私の腕が大丈夫かっていう心配あるかもしれませんが、全然あの書いちゃうんで、思いを込めて書いちゃうんでね、
so you might worry if my arm will be okay, but I put all my heart into it!
あのぜひぜひ、えー、購入していただけたら嬉しいなと思います。よろしくお願いします。
I'd be so happy if you would purchase it. Thank you!
えー、注意事項なのですが、今回のアルバムの到着時期がですね、誕生日グッズよりも早めに発送できる予定になっておりますので、早くアルバムが欲しい方は、カートをね、誕生日グッズと分けて、注文をしてください。
Regarding shipping, the album is scheduled to be shipped even earlier than birthday goods, so if you want it early, please order the album separately from birthday goods!
アルバムのカートと誕生日グッズのね、カートを一緒にしてしまいますと、誕生日グッズと一緒に届くので、到、到、到、到着が遅くなってしまいますので注意してください。
If you put them in the same cart, delivery will be delayed to match the birthday goods.
そして、配信冒頭でもお知らせしましたが、21時からは鷹嶺ルイ誕生日記念グッズ2024も発売開始されます。こちら。
And as announced at the start of the stream, Takane Lui's 2024 Birthday Commemorative Goods will also go on sale at 21:00!
はい。ビッグタオル、ランダム缶バッチ、おでかけぬいぐるみ、ボディ枕の4種類でフルセットもございます。フルセットには箔押し複製サイン入りチケット風カードと、特典ボイスがついてきます。
We have a full set featuring 4 goods: a big towel, random badge, outing plushie, and body pillow. The full set comes with a card featuring a duplicated handwritten signature and a special voice!
今回は数量限定版をご用意させていただいておりまして、数量限定版には特典カードに直筆メッセージを書いちゃいます。アルバムは直筆サイン、こちらは直筆メッセージになってますのでご注意ください。
This time, a limited-quantity version includes a direct signature message on the special card instead of duplicated, so please check it out!
えー、まだまだあります。21時5分からはですね、『魔眼ウインク』のミュージックビデオがプレミア公開しまーす！イェーイ！
And at 21:05, the music video for "Magank Wink" will premiere!
えー、すごい楽しみに待っていた方もいるんじゃないでしょうか。今回もですね、えー、『オーバード』『バカバカ』『ホロホーク』で、えー、続いて、YMさんに、えー、作っていただきましたMVになっております。すごくかっこいい感じに仕上がっているので、ぜひ見ていただければなと思います。
Following "Overdose," "Baka Pakka," and "Horo Hawk," this MV was produced by YM-san, and it turned out super cool, so I hope you'll check it out!
そんな『魔眼ウインク』をたくさんの人に聴いてもらうために、ハッシュタグ「#魔眼ウインク投稿チャレンジ」キャンペーンも開催中でございます。6月30日までなので要チェックです。
To help spread the word, the "#MagankWink Posting Challenge" campaign is running until June 30th!
そしてここからはコラボのお知らせです。ちょっとね、あの告知が多くなってすいません。コラボのお知らせです。なんと、DAMさんでコラボキャンペーンを実施することになりました！イェーイ！
And finally, a collaborative campaign with DAM will also be held from June 12th to July 31st!
DAMにて課題曲を歌いまいて参加者全員の累計得点が
with the campaign song and achieving a total score
10万点に達しますと
of 100,000 points,
限定メッセージ動画をプレゼントいたします。
we will present a limited message video!
参加してくれた方にはオリジナル壁紙プレゼント、
Participants will receive an original wallpaper,
さらに抽選で10名様にオリジナルステンレスボトルをプレゼント。
and 10 randomly drawn winners will receive an original stainless bottle!
なんかした私見えてるな？プレゼント。DAMでたくさんみんな歌ってくれると嬉しいです。
I'll be so happy if lots of you sing it on DAM!
そんなダムさんにてオーバードの本人映像が本日6月11日から順次配信開始しています。
Starting today, June 11th, at 10:00 PM,
こちら。
Here it is!
はい、ミュージックビデオと一緒にオーバードが歌えるので、この機会に足を運んでみてください。
So please take this chance to sing "Overdose" with the music video!
渋谷のグリコビジョンなど複数箇所でですね、ビジョン放送が決定しました。すげえ！
we've decided to broadcast the 3D live on the Shibuya Vision screens!
こちらね7月頃から放送予定なので、詳細はを待ちいただければなと思います。また詳細発表させていただきます。
It's scheduled to air around July, so please look forward to more details coming soon!
まだまだ嬉しいお知らせがあります。あとあともうちょっとです。
I still have more happy announcements,
6月13日木曜日22時より放送のラジオSCHOOL OF LOCKに私先生として初出演させていただきます！
I'll be making my first appearance as a teacher on "SCHOOL OF LOCK!" on Thursday, June 13th, at 10:00 PM!
はい、ということで生徒の皆さんぜひぜひ聞いてください！はい、嬉しいお知らせをたくさんさせていただきましたが、
So students, be sure to tune in!
ここでですね今日のこのライブを一緒に作ってくれた素敵なバンドメンバーの皆さんをご紹介させていただきたいと思います。
here are the wonderful band members who helped make today's live stream possible.
バンドメンバーの皆さんどうもお待たせしました。え、長くてすみませんね。
Band members, thanks for waiting! Sorry for the long intro!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much!
いぇーい、戻ってきてくれました。
Yay, they came back for us!
というわけでちょっと紹介をしていきましょうかね。準備は大丈夫ですか皆さん？
Now, let's introduce them one by one. Are you ready, everyone?
皆さん大丈夫ですか？うんって頷いてる。
Is everyone okay? Yep, they're nodding.
というわけでバンドメンバーの紹介です。それではベースKさん！
Now, let's introduce the band members starting with our bassist, K-san!
うー、かっこいい！
Ooh, cool!
かっこいいよね。やっぱりベースって低音でかっこいいよね。ありがとうございます。
The bass has such a cool, deep sound. Thank you so much!
そしてキーボードくわっちさん！
And on keyboard, Kuwacchi-san!
うー、おしゃれですね。
Ooh, stylish!
やんちゃ、やんちゃですね。ありがとうございます。
So playful, right? Thank you so much!
そしてギターカルロスさん！
And on guitar, Carlos-san!
うー、かっこいいぜ。ありがとうございます。
Ooh, so cool! Thank you so much!
いや、かっこいいな。
Yeah, so cool.
はい、そして最後にバンドマスターでドラム、ドラムでバンドマスターをしてくださったぐーさん！
And last but not least, our band master and drummer, Gu-san!
うー、やかっこいいですね。ありがとうございます。
Ooh, so cool! Thank you so much!
そしてですね、あのこのメンバーにはちょっとあの
And you know, these members...
あのこう言うね、あの3Dでは登場していないんですけれどもちゅうことで。
they aren't here in 3D with us,
裏にですね、マニプのパスタさんがいます。ありがとうございます。あ、ピルルルルー私がじゃ交換をピルル、あ、手振ってくれてますね。ありがとうございます。
but behind us, we have Pasta-san from Maple! Thank you! Ah, pirurururu... Oh, you're waving at us? Thank you so much!
というメンバーでお送りさせていただきました。
That's the team we put this on with!
ということであとね2曲歌わせていただくんですけども、21時15分からはメンバーシップ限定ライブもこの生バンドでお届けしたいと思います。
Now, we have two more songs to perform, and starting at 9:15 PM, we'll also be streaming the membership-only live portion with this exact live band!
この機会にぜひメンバーシップに参加してみてください。
I hope you'll all take this chance to join the membership!
ということで、ええ、まだやっていない2曲がありますね。
So, we still have two songs left to go.
次の曲はですね、え、夢ができたのと いう曲になるんですけども、これは私がえ、ホロライブに入る前、ホロライブを見つけて、あ、ホロライブに入りたいなって思った、えその、え思いのままを書いていただいた、書き下ろしていただいた楽曲になります。
The next song is "Yume ga Dekita no." It's a song I wrote based on the feelings I had right before I found Hololive, thinking, "Ah, I want to join Hololive!"
はい、聞いていただきたいんですが、
Please give it a listen.
その前に、え、水を飲みます。
But before that, I'm going to grab a drink of water!
ちょっとすみません、水を飲ませてください。
Sorry, let me just have some water.
ね、このままいったらエモいやんって思ったでしょ？
You probably thought, "Going straight into it would be so emotional," right?
え、ちょっと水飲まないとやっていけなかったんで、水を飲ませていただきました。
Well, I wouldn't have made it through without drinking some water, so I had to take a quick break!
ということで皆さん準備は大丈夫ですかね？はい。ということで、ちょっと、ええ、ホロライブに入って私のね、たくさん夢が叶っていたんですけども、やっぱり
So, everyone ready?
ホロライブにも目指した、えきっかけっていうの、思いは忘れたくないなと、思いましてこの曲を歌わせていただきます。聞いてください。
hololive is what led me here, so I never want to forget that driving motivation. That's the feeling I put into singing this song. Please listen.
夢ができたの
I found a dream.
そこは私が憧れた星たちの世界
It's the world of stars I've always admired,
両手いっぱいの愛を持ち寄って
bringing together hands full of love
明かりにしている
and making it a light.
まちがいのことだけ
Only wrapping around mistakes,
包むような明かり
a light that embraces them.
夢でできたの
Dreams made this
この地球の夜は暗いでしょう
Earth's night, isn't it dark?
どんなときでもとびっきり優しい
No matter when, exceptionally kind
灯火になりたいの
I want to be a beacon of light.
湯舟に愚痴を浮かべて泣いた
Floating my complaints in the tub and crying,
昨日の私は
yesterday's me
ネガティブごと丸めて捨てて
bundled up all my negativity and threw it away,
生まれ変わったの
and was reborn.
高い壁があるなら
If there is a high wall,
当たって砕いちゃえ
hit it and smash it to pieces!
ひとりきりでは
All alone,
この地球の夜は暗いでしょう
this Earth's night is dark, isn't it?
きみの明日を照らし出すような
Lighting up your tomorrow,
灯火になりたいの
I want to be a beacon of light.
夢でできたの
Dreams made this
この地球の夜は暗いでしょう
Earth's night, isn't it dark?
どんなときでもとびっきり優しい
No matter when, exceptionally kind
灯火になりたいの
I want to be a beacon of light.
はい、ということで夢ができたのをお聴かせいただきました。
And with that, you've heard "Yume ga Dekita no."
そして、えー次が本当に最後の曲になります。
And now, um, this will truly be our final song.
今日は本当にみなさん集まってくれて応援してくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you so much everyone for gathering and supporting me today.
えーちょっとね喉が不完全ではあるのでまたねなんかリベンジしたいななんて
Um, my throat isn't 100%, so I'd love to get my revenge again someday, haha!
リベンジさせていただきたいなと思います。はい。
I'd really love a rematch. Yes.
すごい生バンドライブ初のエースの試みだったんですがすごく楽しかったです。
This was my first attempt at a live band concert, and it was so much fun.
これからも鷹嶺ルイ頑張っていきたいと思いますのでみなさん応援ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
I'll keep working hard as Takane Lui, so everyone, please keep cheering me on!
夢はソロライブ！
My dream is a solo live!
頑張って叶えるぞ！
I'll work hard to make it happen!
ということでちょっとお水を飲んで...
With that, I'm going to grab a quick drink of water...
最後の曲は私が作詞に参加させていただきました。
The final song is one I participated in writing the lyrics for.
鷹嶺ルイへの感謝の気持ちを込めて歌いたいと思います。聴いてください、翼。
I want to sing it filled with gratitude toward Takane Lui. Please listen to "Tsubasa."
大丈夫、僕の中
It's okay, inside me...
鳥カゴにフリーキーショー
A free key show in a birdcage,
鍵開けて?「私のセカイ」
unlocking "My World"?
開幕初手無限リスタートです
The curtain rises with an infinite restart,
で?キミはカゴの虜
So, you're the cage's captive.
泣かないで
Don't cry inside,
でも無理に笑わないで
even so, don't force a smile.
ゆっくりに見上げとよ
Gently look up at it,
得たものを通して翼を痛めつけて
piercing through things with your wings.
今度は私が支えるから
This time, I'm the one who will support you,
歪んだ夢に涙した日もあったけど
even though I cried into your twisted dreams.
君の言う大丈夫で諦めずに超えた まだ遅くないよここから始まるソウリ
Don't give up just yet, your story is just beginning.
さあ
Let's go.
少し進んで
Walk a little further,
涙を拭いて歩き出そう
wiping away your tears as you go.
覚えてる私もね 抱いかけた翼抱いて 励まそう
I remember too, embracing my own wings to encourage you,
君に怯えてた
holding you close.
ほらあの日のこと 雨上がりの切なさに 私たちは強く
On that rainy day, we grew stronger together in our agonizing pain.
生まれ変わる 心ない声に 耳をすませば
Hear our rebirth in our voiceless cries,
痛みもあるけど 見た目がここにいる 出会っては任せたよ
though there's pain, having you here with me means I can let go.
また増えていくよ
Let's keep moving forward!
これからのエールに さあ手をともに合って
Call out to the sky and meet with hands joined,
遥か彼方の顔を見つめよう
gazing at a faraway sky.
これから先は 傷つけずに進めない
From now on, I won't let us get hurt anymore,
だけど覚えてて 君はもう一人じゃないから
but since I have you, I won't be alone.
胸を張って
So open your heart.
私たち今も 不器用で無邪気なことに 譲れない夢抱いて
We're still clumsy, never letting go of our reckless dreams,
翼羽ばたかせよ
let our wings burst open.
今日は来てくれて本当にありがとう!
Thank you so much for coming today!
強い風を受けて 高く高く飛べたとも
Catching the wind, soaring high and proud,
また雨が降り出しても 私が守るから
even if the rain starts falling again, I'll protect you.
この先にどんな 未来が待ってるか わからない
I don't know what kind of future awaits us,
だけど信じている 君とならどこまでも行ける
but if I believe in you, I can go anywhere.
一緒に見る夢のストーリー
Let's live out our dream story together!
今日はみんな来てくれてありがとう!
Thank you all so much for coming today!
すごい楽しい誕生日になりました!
I'm so happy to celebrate this amazing birthday with you all!
アルバムもグッズもよろしくね ソロライブの夢叶いよ アーティストボイス そしてね、and YOU! ありがとうございました!
May all our live dreams come true! Thank you so much!